Nelluri Gopi

gopi.137n@gmail.com +91 9515815396

Career Objective

Microsoft Azure DevOps professional offering a distinguished and insightful exposure of around 5+ years of experience across high-growth environments in cloud & production support, implementation, configuring, monitoring and troubleshooting in Azure cloud. Enthusiastic while working as part of a team or alone and believes in hard-work discipline and perseverance.

Professional Summary

- 1. I have 5+ years of experience in IT, as a Cloud DevOps engineer with over 3.6 years of experience in Azure Cloud, DevOps, Configuration management, Infrastructure automation, Continuous Integration and Delivery (CI/CD). I can implement effective strategies for
- N Tier application development in both Cloud and On-premises environments.
- 2. Expertise in Architecting and Implementing Azure Service Offering, such as Azure cloud services, Azure storage, Azure Active Directory (AD), Azure Resource.
- 3. Experience in various Cloud service models, including laaS, PaaS, and SaaS and supporting deployment models, including Private, Public, and Hybrid cloud.
- 4. Configuring and managing Virtual Machines using Windows Azure portal, configuring and monitoring Cloud services.
- 5. Proven experience on creates Branching and Tagging concepts in Version Control tool like VSTS with GIT.
- 6. Having Expertise knowledge in configuring the Site-to-Site and Point-to-Site VPN connections.
- 7. Experience in PowerShell scripting for automation of Azure resources.
- 8. Good exposure in Azure networking, Storage Account, Storage Explorer, VM provisioning, Automation, Monitoring, AZ Copy, AD, Application Insights, Azure Roles, ARM etc.
- 9. Expertise in Azure Scalability and Azure Availability Build VMs availability sets using the Azure portal to provideresiliency for IaaS based solution and Virtual Machine Scale Sets (VMSS) using Azure Resource Manager (ARM) to manage network traffic.
- 10. Proficient in ARM templates, automated few ARM resource creations using ARM templates.
- 11. Configured Azure Virtual Networks (VNets), subnets, Azure network settings, CIDR address blocks, DNS settings, security policies.
- 12. Installing, Configuring and managing of Active Directory, DNS, IIS and FILE servers.
- 13. Exposed Virtual machines and cloud services in the VNets to the Internet using Azure External Load Balancer.
- 14. Extensive experience in PowerShell scripting to automate many services management in Azure.
- 15. Hands on Replication services LRS, ZRS and GRS, Good Knowledge in Database like SQL Server, MySQL.
- 16. Implemented a CI/CD pipeline using Azure DevOps (VSTS, TFS) in both cloud and on-premises with GIT, MS Build, Docker along with Jenkins plugins.
- 17. Implemented high availability with Azure Resource Manager deployment models.
- 18. Designed Network Security Groups (NSGs) to control inbound and outbound access to network interfaces (NICs), VMs and subnets.
- 19. Expertise in Blob storage and File storage and Configured PAAS services like App service, App service plan.
- 20. Deploying web pages into azure app services (PaaS) using File server.
- 21. Adding, removing, or updating user account information, resetting passwords.

- 22. Executing builds and troubleshooting, Interaction with development and QA teams.
- 23. Managed environments DEV, QA, UAT and PROD for various releases and designed instance.
- 24. Handled daily builds for multiple projects, implementation and configuring of Azure backup.

Technical Skills

Cloud Platform: Microsoft Azure

DevOps Tools: Azure DevOps, Docker, Kubernetes

CI/CD Tools : Azure DevOps Operating Systems : Windows

Scripting Language: PowerShell scripting, ARM Templates, Terraform

Ticketing Tools: ServiceNow, JIRA

Experience Summary

1. Worked as Azure Cloud Engineer at Nityo Info Tech from Dec 2023 to March 2024.

- 2. Worked as Software Engineer at First Source from September 2022 to July 2023.
- 3. Worked as Support Engineer at Venus Cyber Tech from November 2018 to Sept 2022.

Education Details

B. TECH MECH 2018 from Anurag Engineering College Ananthagiri JNTUH.

Project 1

Project Title: Card Services Role: Azure Cloud Engineer

Duration: Dec 2023 to March 2024

Roles and Responsibilities:

- 1 Involved in the process of hosting/deploying the entire application into Azure ReadHat Openshift(ARO).
- 2 Deployed the Spring boot web applications into different ARO clusters.
- 3 Deployed all their applications through yam and teckton pipeline.
- 4 Scaling up and scaling down the clusters and pods and containers in ARO portal.
- 5 Creating The PV and PVC storage's for their applications.
- 6 Private Endpoints and DNS a records deployments using terraform.
- 7 Responsible for creating Network Security Groups and add inbound rules.
- 8 Create storage accounts for DEV, QA, CERT, PROD and DR environments for their application development and testing purpose.
- 9 Creating Key vaults for DEV, QA, CERT, PROD and DR environments for storing the secrets and certificates

purpose.

10 Creating the Azure resources using terraform code through Terraform cloud to maintaining the state files for

individually for each environment.

- 11 Adding addition disks to Azure VM upon receiving request.
- 12 Managing entire Azure infrastructure services.
- 13 Create web apps for developers to do development work.
- 14 Update files with infrastructure details like storage account details etc..
- 15 Working with the application Owner for the Data assessment and Getting Approvals.

16 Assist customers with Azure and GitHub templates, ASM to ARM migrations and on premise to Cloud Migrations.

Project 2

Project Title: Axiom Infra Role: Software Engineer

Duration: Sept 2022 to July 2023

Roles and Responsibilities:

- 1 Managing Azure Resource Groups, VM Compute, VNet, Storage, and Azure Active Directory.
- 2 VM deployments by using Azure portal and terraform script.
- 3 Write PowerShell and schedule to shutdown virtual machines during off business hours.
- 4 Creation of Azure NIC, Azure Virtual networks, Azure VM?s and provide access users.
- 5 Responsible for creating Network Security Groups and add inbound rules.
- 6 Adding addition disks to Azure VM upon receiving request.
- 7 Provide read access of Azure subscription to users upon approvals from higher management.
- 8 Proficiency in setting up high availability and disaster recovery solutions for Azure SQL Databases, such as implementing failover groups, geo-replication, or automated backups.
- 9 Auto and scale down various services like VMs, SQL Servers (DTUs) workloads.
- 10 Worked on Azure services involving in software design and implementation of various.
- 11 Client Server applications with MS-SQL Server 2005, 2008, Microsoft Azure, My SQL, JSON etc.
- 12 Provide read access of Azure subscription to users upon approvals from higher management.
- 13 Proficient in working with Azure Boards, Azure Repos, Azure Pipelines, Azure Test Plans, and Azure Artifacts.
- 14 Proficient in working with Git and visual studio code.
- 15 Experience in setting up and configuring CI/CD pipelines using Azure Pipelines or similar tools.

Project 3

Project Title: Intria Management services

Role: Azure Cloud Engineer

Duration: Nov 2020 to Sept 2022

Roles and Responsibilities:

- 1 Involved in the process of hosting/deploying the entire application into Microsoft Azure Cloud.
- 2 VM deployments using portal and terraform.
- 3 Responsible for creating Network Security Groups and add inbound rules.
- 4 Write PowerShell and schedule to shutdown virtual machines during off business hours.
- 5 Create storage accounts for dev & QA teams for their application development and testing purpose.
- 6 Create ARM templates to reuse similar deployment with some standard configurations and naming conventions.
- 7 Create PowerShell script to manage multiple subscriptions in Classic portal using publish settings file.
- 8 Create users in Azure AD from Portal as well as form Power Shell.

- 9 Migration of Azure VM?s from Classic portal to ARM portal.
- 10 Migration of IAAS services like virtual network, network interface etc.
- 11 Adding addition disks to Azure VM upon receiving request.
- 12 Creation of Azure NIC, Azure Virtual networks, Azure VM?s and provide access users.
- 13 Managing entire Azure infrastructure services.
- 14 Create web apps for developers to do development work.
- 15 Update files with infrastructure details like SQL connection string, storage account details etc.
- 16 Provide read access of Azure subscription to users upon approvals from higher management.
- 17 Preparing the recovery services vault and finalize the azure resources.
- 18 Working with the application Owner for the Data assessment and Getting Approvals.
- 19 Assist customers with Azure and GitHub templates, ASM to ARM migrations and on premise to Cloud Migrations.

Project 4

Project Title: Assurity Life Insurance

Role: Support Engineer

Duration: April 2019 to July 2020

Roles and Responsibilities:

- 1 Providing technical support for Azure customers, resolving issues, and troubleshooting problems.
- 2 Provide systems support including responding to monitoring alerts.
- 3 Collaborating with cross-functional teams to design, implement, and maintain Azure-based solutions.
- 4 Monitoring Azure resources, optimizing performance, and ensuring security compliance.
- 5 Azure Administration Tasks & Troubleshooting on Azure Service.
- 6 Experience managing and prioritizing support cases to ensure timely resolution.
- 7 Participating in on-call rotations and providing 24/7 support as required.
- 8 Conducting performance tuning and optimization of Azure services for clients.

Declaration

Thereby declare that the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge. I will abide	: by
the service andconduct	
rules of the company.	

Place:	
(Gopi	N)

Date: